Hello friends, whenever we buy a motor
insurance or car insurance policy,
we often ask
our advisor whether you have added this 470
depression.
Friends, in today's video, we will learn what is the
definition of zero depression,
why do we have to take it when we are already
buying a first party insurance policy,
why do we have to take zero depression additional, for
how many years do insurance companies
provide this facility, at the end of this video I will
tell you
how you can tell by looking at the policy document whether this policy is zero
depression or a normal first party insurance
policy. Hello friends, my name is
Harvinder Singh and welcome to the DSC
Solutions YouTube channel. Here you will be
able to understand insurance in very simple
language, neither any difficult words have to be
understood nor any policy document,
just watch any 5 to 7 minute
video in which you
want to understand the topic and clear all your doubts.
So friends, let's start with our very first question,
zero decoration i.e. depression or many
people also call it bumper-to-bumper coverage.  What is
this, what is its definition
friends, zero means
nothing and decorative means wear and tear or in other words,
fool, yes, but friends, whenever we
buy anything like car
insurance in this case, then every year there is
some deterioration in it or
its value decreases, we
call it depression and decoration means that by
taking this depreciation and I will
not be charged any depression, do you understand
when we are buying a normal personal insurance then
why is there a need for zero depression because friends, in normal personal
insurance, IRDA does not say
that you will not be charged depression, in that
you will have to pay decoration, Malviya, if your
car becomes 3 years old then according to that policy
you will be charged patience every year,
but if you have taken zero
depression or new updates reviews and depreciation in your policy then there will be
no negative charge, let us
understand this as an example, but a car meets with an
accident and
some points in its Claremont have to be replaced or
repaired  It costs
20 thousand rupees and if there is
no zero decoration and decoration in your body then there will be a
slide charge of depression on it,
suppose the rate of depression is 50%, then out of the fort of 20000 rupees
in your normal first party insurance,
you will get only 10
thousand rupees as a claim, but
if there is zero depression or will be presented in your policy, then
you will
get the entire 20000 rupees as a claim, that is, no
wear and tear or basic wear and tear depression will be
charged, so friends,
we have to take this policy for almost new vehicles,
when the value of the vehicle is very high, the
value of its parts is very high, at that
time we should
take a policy for road which is ended, friends, let's talk about
how many years these companies provide this coverage,
see, in this most of the companies, almost
all the companies give us this coverage for 5 years
because I told you that
it is more needed in a new vehicle
because all the parts are new, there is
more damage due to depression on it, so
even after 5 years, some companies provide this coverage for 5 years
And some companies will give you this cover for 10 years
but there is a condition in it that the
discounting will be reduced and this don't cover will be
expensive for you, but still if
you feel that you should take protection,
you do not have to pay the value of your vehicle at the
time of depression claim, then you
can take this don't cover later also, so
friends now comes the turn that
how will you understand by looking at a policy document whether there is
zero depression cover in it or not,
for this you have to do a very simple thing
as it will be displayed on the screen, in this
you have to go to the phone damage
section, that is, the section in which the
premium for coverage of damage to your own vehicle is written, you have to go to that section
and there you have to check whether any such
word like depression or training hero depression is written in front of it, its
premium should be written, the amount for which
you have paid for this cream, if
you see
this premium paid in the goosebumps section of your policy document, then
your policy is zero damage
and if you have not paid this cream, then
this Tulsi is not your product  Normally,
first-party insurance can be just that,
or it can also be a third-party insurance policy.
So, this way, you can check
your coverage in full sunlight.
Friends, as far as zero-depression is concerned,
it doesn't bring any additional coverage.
It simply doesn't allow you to incur depression charges
whenever you
take it, meaning the coverage remains the same. All the
parts covered are covered under standard
costing. However,
in normal first-party insurance, there is a
decoration charge. Since there is
no decoration charge, it does
n't allow for decoration expenses to be charged, thus
promoting your flavor demand. So,
friends, I've
told you all about zero-depression. In a
little bit, there are
many such additions, such as consumables,
engine protectors, return to invoices, which are
quite advanced and can be added
to a passport insurance policy. If
you want detailed information about them,
go to the playlist and the link is
given in the description.
Go to the motor insurance playlist and
check out Hi Dad
there in detail.  But information has been given, so
friends, I hope you liked this topic
and you must have understood the information
so that whatever premium you spend on your
SIM, none of your money should be
wasted because you have
understood this very well, so friends, I hope that we will
meet you in good health and happiness in the next video, till then please
allow me, take care of yourself,
stay happy, thank you
[Music]